Guide to the James Marshall Osborn Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Box and Folder List, 1960
  - Stevenson, Lionel, 1935-73 (Box 71, Folder 1496)
    St Catherine's, Oxford, UCLA, Duke
  - Stewart, Powell, 1955-56 (Box 71, Folder 1497)
    University of Texas, periodical indexing on computer
  - Stewart, Stanley, 1964-66 (Box 71, Folder 1498)
  - Stone, George Winchester, Jr., 1950-75 (Box 71, Folder 1499)
    MLA, 18th century, etc.
  - Stone, Lawrence, 1961 (Box 71, Folder 1500)
    Whythorne preface
  - Stonehill, C. A., 1938-68 (Box 71, Folder 1501)
    (Robert J. Barry, Sr. and Jr.), Booksellers
  - Storm, Colton, 1951-54 (Box 71, Folder 1502)
    Clements Library, University of Michigan
  - Straker, Henry P., 1959-71 (Box 71, Folder 1503)
    English friend
  - Strauss, Albrecht B., 1958-72 (Box 71, Folder 1504)
  - Street, Wolcott Davenport, 1936-74 (Box 71, Folder 1505)
    Old friend, fund-raiser
  - Stroh, Charles, 1944-69 (Box 72, Folder 1506-1507)
    Hartford lawyer, Holstein breeder, good friend
  - Strong, Roy and Julia Trevelyan Oman, 1969-72 (Box 72, Folder 1508)
  - Stryker, Philip Fitzhugh, 1963 (Box 72, Folder 1509)
  - Stubbs, Kendon, 1967-73 (Box 72, Folder 1510)
    Reference librarian, University of Virginia Library
  - Sturges, Hale, 1956-58 (Box 72, Folder 1511)
    Wing, Dryden
  - Sturges, Wesley Alba, 1949-61 (Box 72, Folder 1512)
    Dean, Yale Law School
  - Suffolk, Charles Henry George Howard, 20th Earl of, 1906-1941, 1940-49 (Box 72, Folder 1513)
  - Super, Robert, 1936-63 (Box 72, Folder 1514)
    University of Michigan, Landor
  - Sutcliffe, William Denham, 1913-1964, 1940-74 (Box 72, Folder 1515)
  - Sutherland, James Runcieman, 1900-, 1938-76 (Box 72, Folder 1516-1518)
    University of London, Oxford, friend
  - Sutherland, Lucy Stuart, Dame, 1903-, 1968-76 (Box 72, Folder 1519)
    Oxford, Macartney, etc.
  - Swedenberg, Hugh Thomas, 1906-, 1940-75 (Box 72, Folder 1520)
  - Swem, Earl G., 1941 (Box 72, Folder 1521)
    Librarian, William and Mary College
  - Sweney, John R., 1968-74 (Box 72, Folder 1522)
    Colby College, Maine, Dryden
  - Sylvester, Richard Standish, 1926-1978, 1958-73 (Box 72, Folder 1523)
    Yale English Department, More
  - Szladits, Lola, 1973-76 (Box 72, Folder 1524)
    Curator, Berg Collection, New York Public Library
  - Tanis, James Robert, 1928-, 1965-68 (Box 73, Folder 1525)
  - Tate, Elizabeth (Nelson), 1957-76 (Box 73, Folder 1526)
    Very close friend
  - Tatlock, J. S. P., 1938 (Box 73, Folder 1527)
    MLA and Work in Progress
  - Taylor, Robert H., 1963-69 (Box 73, Folder 1528)
    Collector, Princeton
  - Teachout, Alda R., 1953-64 (Box 73, Folder 1529)
    relative
  - Tedeschi, John, 1970-73 (Box 73, Folder 1530)
  - Tennyson, G. B., 1974-75 (Box 73, Folder 1531)
    UCLA, Stead papers
  - F. S. Thackeray, 1955 (Box 73, Folder 1532)
    Mayor of Winchester, England
  - Thistlethwaite, Frank, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 1533)
    Vice Chancellor, University of East Anglia
  - Thomas, Alan G., 1957-73 (Box 73, Folder 1534)
  - Thomas, Donald, 1962 (Box 73, Folder 1535)
    Fielding
  - Thompson, E. A., 1946-48 (Box 73, Folder 1536)
    Bookbinding
  - Thompson, James Daniel, 1941-69 (Box 73, Folder 1537)
  - Thompson, Lawrence, 1935-68 (Box 73, Folder 1538-1539)
    Curator of Rare Books, Princeton, Rare Books, Inc.
  - Thorne, Samuel, Jr., 1946-69 (Box 73, Folder 1540)
  - Thornton, Francis Beauchesne, 1953 (Box 73, Folder 1541)
  - Thorpe, James Ernest, 1915-, 1955-75 (Box 73, Folder 1542)
    Princeton, Director, Huntington Library
  - Thorpe, Janet, 1969-70 (Box 73, Folder 1543)
    Cooper-Hewitt Museum of Design
  - Tibbetts, Julie, 1944-50 (Box 74, Folder 1544)
    Connecticut War Council
  - Tierney, James E., 1974-76 (Box 74, Folder 1545)
    University of Missouri, St. Louis, Dodsley
  - Tillotson, Arthur, 1938-39 (Box 74, Folder 1546)
    University Library Cambridge
  - Tillotson, Geoffrey, 1964 (Box 74, Folder 1547)
    18th century
  - The Times (London) and TLS, 1938-74 (Box 74, Folder 1548)
  - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963, 1937-54 (Box 74, Folder 1549)
    Keeper of Rare Books, Yale 18th century progenitor
  - Tobin, James, 1941-50 (Box 74, Folder 1550)
    Fordham, STC
  - Todd, William B., 1951-73 (Box 74, Folder 1551)
    University of Texas, 18th century bibliography
  - Torrence, Naomi de L., 1974-76 (Box 74, Folder 1552)
  - Townsend, A. C., 1956 (Box 74, Folder 1553)
    British Museum (Natural History), Banks
  - Tracy, Clarence, 1940-73 (Box 74, Folder 1554)
    University of British Columbia, 18th century
  - Trapp, Joseph, 1965-70 (Box 74, Folder 1555)
    Warburg Institute, London
  - Travis, Clayton Vincent ("Bump"), 1936-57 (Box 74, Folder 1556)
  - Travis, Harold G. ("Red"), 1966-73 (Box 74, Folder 1557)
  - Traylen, Charles W., 1953 (Box 74, Folder 1558)
  - Troxell, Gilbert and Janet (Camp), 1949-60 (Box 74, Folder 1559)
  - Trypanis, Constantine, 1960-72 (Box 74, Folder 1560)
  - Tuller, Robert N., 1935-73 (Box 74, Folder 1561-1562)
    Municipal bonds friend
  - Tullis, Frederick W., 1957-67 (Box 74, Folder 1563)
  - Tunnard, Christopher, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 1564)
    Yale Art and Architecture, proposed for RSA
  - Tuve, Rosemund, 1936-42 (Box 74, Folder 1565)
  - Ure, Peter, 1962 (Box 75, Folder 1566)
    University of Durham, Blount portrait
  - Urmy, Keith M., 1952-71 (Box 75, Folder 1567)
  - Urquhart of Craigston, Bruce, 1960-67 (Box 75, Folder 1568)
    Urquhart epigram
  - van Beeck, Frans Joseph, S. J., 1960-61 (Box 75, Folder 1569)
    Sherburne
  - VanderPoel, Halsted, 1957-76 (Box 75, Folder 1570)
    Johnsonian, collector
  - Van Nosdell, G. A., 1950-51 (Box 75, Folder 1571)
  - Vatican Library, 1936-61 (Box 75, Folder 1572)
  - Verco, Walter J., 1956 Nov 1 (Box 75, Folder 1573)
    College of Arms, Whythorne pedigree
  - Vesper, Arthur F., 1947-50 (Box 75, Folder 1574)
  - Vieth, David M., 1951-76 (Box 75, Folder 1575-1578)
    Southern Illinois University, Rochester, 17th century poetry
  - Vietor, Alexander Orr, 1913-, 1957-75 (Box 75, Folder 1579)
    Curator of Maps, Yale, Elizabethan Club
  - Vincent, Howard P., 1950-53 (Box 75, Folder 1580)
    Wycherley
  - Vincitorio, G. L., 1961-68 (Box 75, Folder 1581)
  - Viner, Jacob, 1947-70 (Box 75, Folder 1582)
  - Von Scherling, Erik, 1951-57 (Box 75, Folder 1583)
  - Vosper, Robert, 1976 (Box 75, Folder 1584)
    Clark Library
  - Vowles, Richard Beckman, 1948-69 (Box 75, Folder 1585)
    University of Florida, University of Wisconsin, POAS
  - Waingrow, Marshall, 1971-72 (Box 76, Folder 1586)
    Claremont Graduate School, Boswell
  - Waith, Eugene, 1942-76 (Box 76, Folder 1587)
    Yale English Department, Elizabethan Club, Boys Friendly, etc.
  - Walbridge, Earl F., 1952 (Box 76, Folder 1588)
    Bibliographical Society of America
  - Walker, Alice, 1954-55 (Box 76, Folder 1589)
    English Inst. paper
  - Walker, Ralph, 1953-73 (Box 76, Folder 1590)
    Twining and Burney, Oxford
  - Wallace, John, 1972-73 (Box 76, Folder 1591)
    University of Chicago, Newberry talk
  - Walton, Clarence, 1945 (Box 76, Folder 1592)
    Massachusetts Committee on Public Safety
  - Walton, Francis R., 1965-66 (Box 76, Folder 1593)
    Gennadino Library, Athens, Neo-Hellenism
  - Walton, James, 1965-67 (Box 76, Folder 1594)
    Trinity College, Dublin, Malone
  - Ward, Charles E., 1936-69 (Box 76, Folder 1595-1599)
    Duke University, Dryden
  - Ward, John, 1958-62 (Box 76, Folder 1600)
    Musicologist (lute and gittern), Braye Lute Book, Harvard
  - Warfel, Betty, 1961-69 (Box 76, Folder 1601)
  - Wark, Robert R., 1973-74 (Box 76, Folder 1602)
    Curator, Huntington Library
  - Wasch, William K., 1968-76 (Box 76, Folder 1603)
    Wesleyan Alumni Sec.
  - Wasserman, Earl R., 1940-61 (Box 76, Folder 1604)
    Pope, Spence, etc.
  - Watson, Francis J. B., 1969 (Box 76, Folder 1605)
    The Wallace Collection, W. S. Lewis's candidacy for Society of Antiquaries
  - Watson, George, 1953-68 (Box 76, Folder 1606)
    Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature
  - Watson, William Weldon, 1940-47 (Box 76, Folder 1607)
    Yale physicist and friend
  - Webber, Joan, 1964-67 (Box 77, Folder 1608)
    Ohio State, Traherne
  - Weber, Kurt, 1936 (Box 77, Folder 1609)
  - Wector, Dixon, 1939-41 (Box 77, Folder 1610)
    UCLA, Burke, etc.
  - Weinbrot, Howard, 1965-76 (Box 77, Folder 1611)
    University of Wisconsin, 18th century
  - Welch, G. Harold, Sr. and Jr., 1940-73 (Box 77, Folder 1612)
    New Haven friends, stocks, etc.
  - Wellek, Albert, 1968-69 (Box 77, Folder 1613)
    Brother of Rene
  - Wellek, Rene, 1903-, 1939-76 (Box 77, Folder 1614-1619)
    University of Iowa, Yale, Comparative Literature, close friend
  - Wellesz, Egon, 1960 (Box 77, Folder 1620)
  - Wells, David A., 1972-73 (Box 77, Folder 1621)
    Editor, MHRA Annual Bulletin
  - Wells, John Edwin, 1942 (Box 77, Folder 1622)
    MLA program
  - Wenner, Evelyn W., 1950-69 (Box 77, Folder 1623)
    Stevens scholar
  - Wenzel, Siegfried and Elizabeth (Brown), 1961-66 (Box 77, Folder 1624)
    Fasciculum morum and Whythorne
  - Wesleyan University, 1939-69 (Box 77, Folder 1625-1626)
  - Wesleyan, Class of 1928, 1938-68 (Box 77, Folder 1627)
  - Weston, John C., 1961-63 (Box 77, Folder 1628)
    University of Massachusetts, Burke, L. F. Powell's visit
  - Wheelock, Richard, 1965 (Box 78, Folder 1629)
    Stock and Malone
  - Wheelwright, Philip, 1950-51 (Box 78, Folder 1630)
    Dartmouth, English Inst.
  - Wheen, Arthur, 1947-52 (Box 78, Folder 1631)
    Victoria and Albert Museum
  - Whicher, George F., 1941-53 (Box 78, Folder 1632)
  - White, Elizabeth Wade, 1954-74 (Box 78, Folder 1633)
  - White, Eric Walter, 1960-73 (Box 78, Folder 1634-1635)
    Arts Council of Great Britain, Britten, Burney, Stravinsky, etc.
  - White, F. P., 1961 (Box 78, Folder 1636)
    Librarian, St. John's College Cambridge
  - White, H. Adelbert, 1941-49 (Box 78, Folder 1637)
    University of Nebraska, proposed subject index to STC
  - White, Helen C., 1942-45 (Box 78, Folder 1638)
    University of Wisconsin, 17th century newsletter
  - White, Wallace, 1940 (Box 78, Folder 1639)
    Son of friends whom J. M. Osborn recommended to Wesleyan
  - Whitehorn, Michael D., 1970 (Box 78, Folder 1640)
    Whythorne descendant (collateral)
  - Whitehorn, Roy D., 1956-61 (Box 78, Folder 1641)
    Collateral descendant of Whythorne
  - Whitehorne, Joseph W. A., III, 1956 Feb 19 (Box 78, Folder 1642)
    Descendant of Whythorne
  - Whitney, Reed and Virginia, 1953-60 (Box 78, Folder 1643)
    Old friends from Kenilworth, Illinois
  - Whythorne book, OUP, 1959-62 (Box 78, Folder 1644)
  - Wicklow, William Cecil James Philip John Paul Howard, 8th Earl of, 1902-, 1951-52 (Box 78, Folder 1645)
    Henry Colman MS
  - Wikelund, Philip R., 1954-64 (Box 78, Folder 1646)
    Walker scholar, Indiana University
  - Wilcox, Maud, 1967-68 (Box 78, Folder 1647)
    Humanities Editor, Harvard University Press
  - Wilder, Isabel, 1964-75 (Box 78, Folder 1648)
    Sister of Thornton Wilder
  - Wilding, C. F., 1941 (Box 78, Folder 1649)
  - Wiles, R. M., 1957 (Box 78, Folder 1650)
    English professor at McMaster University
  - Wiley, Margaret Lee, 1951 (Box 78, Folder 1651)
    Spence scholar, East Texas State Teachers' College
  - Wilkinson, C. H., 1955-58 (Box 78, Folder 1652)
    Worcester College, Oxford
  - Willard, C. Lawson, 1949-57 (Box 78, Folder 1653)
    Rector of Trinity Church on the Green, New Haven
  - William Salt Library, Stafford, England, 1959-66 (Box 78, Folder 1654)
    Malone queries
  - Williams, Aubrey, 1959-75 (Box 78, Folder 1655)
    University of Florida, Pope, Yale friends, etc.
  - Williams, Franklin B., 1941-72 (Box 78, Folder 1656)
    Elizabethan scholar, Georgetown University
  - Williams, Sir Harold, 1952-67 (Box 78, Folder 1657)
    Swift scholar
  - Williams, Stanley T., 1938-54 (Box 78, Folder 1658)
  - Williamson, George, 1958 (Box 78, Folder 1659)
    Editor of Modern Philology, University of Chicago
  - Willoughby, Edwin E., 1941 (Box 78, Folder 1660)
    Folger, English Inst.
  - Wilson, Alfred, 1949-54 (Box 78, Folder 1661)
  - Wilson, Charles, 1971 (Box 78, Folder 1662)
  - Wilson Frank Percy, 1889-1963, and Joanna (Perry-Keene), 1957-77 (Box 78, Folder 1663)
    Merton Professor of English Literature, Oxford University, Elizabethan scholar
  - Wilson, James Harold, 1948-62 (Box 78, Folder 1664)
    Restoration scholar, Ohio State University
  - Wilson, Keith, 1966-67 (Box 78, Folder 1665)
    Clarinet, Yale School of Music
  - Wimsatt, William Kurtz, 1907-1975, and Margaret (Hecht), 1939-75 (Box 79, Folder 1666-1669)
    Yale English Department, Pope, 18th century, close friend
  - Winchester, Harold P., 1961-62 (Box 79, Folder 1670)
  - Winchester, England, 1954-74 (Box 79, Folder 1671)
    Russell MS of list of "Benefactors to Winchester," deposited there by J. M. Osborn
  - Wing, Donald Goddard, 1904-1972, and Charlotte, 1942-70 (Box 79, Folder 1672)
    Bibliographer, compiler of STC
  - Wing STC, 1973-76 (Box 79, Folder 1673)
  - Winks, Robin W., 1969-71 (Box 79, Folder 1674)
    Cultural attache to U. S. Embassy in London, Yale history department
  - Winton, Calhoun, 1970-75 (Box 79, Folder 1675)
    University of South Carolina
  - Witherspoon, Alec M., 1942-62 (Box 79, Folder 1676)
    Yale English department
  - Withington, Eleanor, 1961-70 (Box 79, Folder 1677)
    Cleveland scholar, Queens College
  - Withington, Sidney, Dorothea, and Virginia, 1955-71 (Box 79, Folder 1678)
  - Withner, Patricia, 1942 (Box 79, Folder 1679)
    Research assistant, periodical index and Work in Progress
  - Witt, Marion, 1949-53 (Box 79, Folder 1680)
    Hunter College, English Inst.
  - Witten, Laurence, 1954-74 (Box 79, Folder 1681)
  - Wittkower, Rudolf, 1966 (Box 79, Folder 1682)
    Burlington scholar
  - Wohrer, Franz-Karl, 1975 (Box 79, Folder 1683)
  - Wolf, Edwin 2nd, 1949-71 (Box 79, Folder 1684)
    Rosenbach, Library Company of Philadelphia
  - Wolf, Mary Hunter, 1971-76 (Box 79, Folder 1685)
    American Shakespeare Theater, friend
  - Wolfe, William P., 1960 (Box 79, Folder 1686)
  - Wolle, Francis, 1939-40 (Box 79, Folder 1687)
    Department of English, University of Colorado
  - Wood, George Alastair M., 1962-74 (Box 79, Folder 1688-1690)
    Librarian of the Osborn Collection 1963-65, Stirling University
  - Wood, J. Richard T., 1968 (Box 79, Folder 1691)
    Dissertation on Stair
  - Woodruff, Patricia, 1970-74 (Box 80, Folder 1692)
    Editor, Yale University Press
  - Woods, Charles B., 1955-62 (Box 80, Folder 1693)
    Editor, Philological Quarterly, Iowa
  - Woods, William, 1952-54 (Box 80, Folder 1694)
    Planned edition of Burney letters
  - Woodward, Arthur M., 1963 (Box 80, Folder 1695)
  - Woodward, Daniel H., 1966-74 (Box 80, Folder 1696)
    Mary Washington College, Huntington Library
  - Woodward, S. M., 1970-71 (Box 80, Folder 1697)
    Spalding Gentleman's Society
  - Woodworth, Mary Katherine, 1939-70 (Box 80, Folder 1698)
    Hayley scholar, English professor, Bryn Mawr
  - Woof, R. S., 1961 (Box 80, Folder 1699)
    Southey
  - Work in Progress, 1938-41 (Box 80, Folder 1700)
  - Woodbridge, Homer, 1931-57 (Box 80, Folder 1701)
    Wesleyan, Department of English, and Dana, daughter
  - Wragg, Thomas S., 1955-70 (Box 80, Folder 1702)
    Chatsworth, keeper, Luttrell
  - Wreden, William P., 1954-64 (Box 80, Folder 1703)
  - Wright, Austin, 1935-67 (Box 80, Folder 1704-1707)
    Spence biographer
  - Wright, Ernest Hunter, 1937-44 (Box 80, Folder 1708)
    English Department, Columbia
  - Wright, H. Bunker, 1946-70 (Box 80, Folder 1709)
    Miami University, Ohio, Prior scholar
  - Wright, Louis B., 1941-57 (Box 80, Folder 1710)
    Director of Folger
  - Wright, Stephen C., 1938-39 (Box 80, Folder 1711)
    Secretary, Friends of the Bodleian
  - Wroth, Lawrence C., 1940-62 (Box 80, Folder 1712)
    John Carter Brown Library, Brown University
  - Wrubel, Thomas Paul, 1963-65 (Box 80, Folder 1713)
    Yale undergraduate and member of MS, Peace Corps, Liberia
  - Wunder, Richard P., 1969 (Box 80, Folder 1714)
    Director, Cooper-Hewitt Museum of Design
  - Wynne, Marjorie Gray, 1917-, 1955-67 (Box 80, Folder 1715)
    E. J. Beinecke Research Librarian
  - XI of Psi Upsilon, 1943-53 (Box 81, Folder 1716)
    J. M. Osborn's Wesleyan fraternity chapter
  - Ximenes Rare Books, 1963-64 (Box 81, Folder 1717)
  - Yaendle, Laetitia, 1971-73 (Box 81, Folder 1718)
    Folger Shakespeare Library
  - Yale University, 1938-72 (Box 81, Folder 1719)
  - Yale University Art Gallery, 1956-67 (Box 81, Folder 1720)
    See also: Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff
  - Yale University Library, 1938-39 (Box 81, Folder 1721)
  - Yale University Press, 1945-75 (Box 81, Folder 1722)
  - Yonge, Theodore, 1968-69 (Box 81, Folder 1723)
  - Young, Douglas, 1963-64 (Box 81, Folder 1724)
    Urquhart scholar, University of Minnesota
  - Young, George B., 1969-74 (Box 81, Folder 1725)
  - Young, Junis, 1939 (Box 81, Folder 1726)
  - Young, Karl, 1938-58 (Box 81, Folder 1727)
  - Young, Robert, 1936 (Box 81, Folder 1728)
  - Zandvoort, R. W., 1970-72 (Box 81, Folder 1729)
    Sydney scholar (Dutch)
  - Zeitlin & Ver Brugge, 1965-66 (Box 81, Folder 1730)
    Booksellers, Los Angeles
  - Zimansky, Curt, 1947-73 (Box 81, Folder 1731-1732)
    Department of English, Iowa, Editor, Philological Quarterly
  - Zuckerman, Arnold, 1962 (Box 81, Folder 1733)
    Richard Mead scholar